A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 3255-6261 FA739B
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Suggestions for finding the best media and messages in family planning mass communications (Reports 003678), 1968 (Box 166)
  Technical assistance -- Pakistan; Charity organization -- Pakistan; Ford Foundation
- A guide to voluntary action in family planning (Reports 003679), 1971 (Box 166)
  vi, 208 p.
  Birth control -- India; Population assistance -- India; India
- Behavioral and social science research in population: suggested approaches to a program of contract research under NICHD auspices (Reports 003680), 1968 (Box 166)
  24 p. -- 32 cm.
  Population research -- Kenya; Social sciences -- Research -- Kenya; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Training for program implementation: An action program (Reports 003681), 1970 (Box 166)
  "A follow-up note for an action program based upon the July 1969 Report to the Commissioner of Family Planning, Ministry of Health and Family Planning, Work, Housing and Urban Development, Government of India." --T.p.
- Husband-wife communication and motivational aspects of population control in an Indian village (Reports 003683), 1968 (Box 166)
  International Division/Asia and the Pacific/India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
  [vi], 118 p.: tables: 22 cm.
  CFPI monograph series,no. 10
  Birth control -- India; Communication in marriage -- India; Family size -- India; Ford Foundation India; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; India
- Comments on programs in India (Reports 003684), 1963 (Box 166)
  Discussion of population and family planning issues in India.
  International Division/Asia and the Pacific;/India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
  Birth control -- India; Population assistance -- India; Ford Foundation India; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; India
- Some problems and needs of family planning (Reports 003685), 1965 (Box 166)
  12 p.: tables: 28 cm.
- In search of influence (Reports 003686), 1967 (Box 166)
  Birth control -- India; Population assistance -- India; Contraception -- Research -- India; Ford Foundation India; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; India
- Report on Family Planning Program Punjab (Reports 003687), 1968 (Box 166)
  22 p. + attachments: tables, charts
  Birth control -- India -- Punjab (State); Contraception -- India -- Punjab (State); Population assistance -- India -- Punjab (State); Ford Foundation India; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; India
- Family planning in India and the Ford Foundation (Reports 003688), 1968 (Box 166)
  Birth control -- India; Population assistance -- India; Ford Foundation. Field Office New Delhi; India
- A report on the perceptions and recommendations of a professional educator regarding teacher education in Nigeria, with an attempt to put curriculum development in the proper perspective (Reports 003689), 1969 (Box 167)
  40 p.
  Teachers -- Training of -- Nigeria; Education and state -- Nigeria; Education -- Nigeria; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Ford Foundation programming in West Africa for the 1970s: Nigeria: programs in economics and management development (Reports 003690), 1971 (Box 167)
  60 p. + appendices: tables
  Economics -- Research -- Nigeria; Economists -- Training of -- Nigeria; Executives -- Training of -- Nigeria; Central planning -- Nigeria; Manpower planning -- Nigeria; Industrial management -- Study and teaching -- Nigeria; Small business -- Research -- Nigeria; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Vocational improvement centres: a successful Nigerian experiment, Spring (Reports 003691), 1972 (Box 167)
  36 p.: ill., tables: 28 cm.
  Paper no. 18.
  Vocational education -- Nigeria; Vocational education -- Africa, West; Technical education -- Nigeria; Technical education -- Africa, West; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- A follow-up study on a seminar on the development and organization of vocational training and technical education (Reports 003692), 1966 (Box 167)
  06290261
  Advisor on industrial management
  Vocational education -- Research -- Scandinavia; Technical education -- Research -- Scandinavia; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
- At loggerheads: an evaluation of two Ford Foundation grants to the American Paper Institute for support of a demonstration training program run by U.S. Research and Development Corporation to upgrade unskilled employees of the Georgia Kraft Company, Marc (Reports 003693), 1972 (Box 167)
  06900119
  American Paper Institute, Inc.
  Demonstration training program to upgrade low-level employees of a southern paper mill.
  67 p.: tables
  Unskilled labor -- Georgia; Unskilled labor -- United States; Discrimination in employment -- Georgia; Discrimination in employment -- United States; Technical education -- Georgia; Technical education -- United States; Occupational training -- Georgia; Georgia Kraft Company
- Future investment and spending policies: A further analysis of where we are and how we might make choices for the future (Reports 003694), 1978 (Box 167, Reel R-9302)
  Finance
  Portfolio management -- United States; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Program budgeting; Strategic planning; Ford Foundation
- Science in Turkey (Reports 003695), 1966 (Box 167)
  Prepared for a Trustees meeting, December 8-9, 1966.
  L69-361
  Science -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Turkey; Education, Higher -- Turkey; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- A second look at the Uh-De Project for Improvement of Education in Hawaii (Reports 003696), 1962 (Box 167)
  06000181
  University of Hawaii At Manoa
  Strengthening of teacher education.
  Education, Higher -- Hawaii -- Curricula; Teachers -- Training of -- Hawaii; Education, Humanistic -- Hawaii; Ford Foundation. Education; University of Hawaii at Manoa
- What have we learned about development in the newly emerging countries since 1950? (Reports 003697), 1964 (Box 167)
  "A talk ... before the Canadian Club of Toronto, March 16, 1964." --P.1.
  11 p. -- 28 cm
  Charity organization -- Developing countries; Technical assistance -- Developing countries; Philanthropy -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Program
- The human factor in economic development (Reports 003698), 1958 (Box 167)
  Technical assistance -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Program
- Personnel administration for emerging countries (Reports 003699), 1967 (Box 167)
  06490478
  Program specialists in public administration at the Algerian National School of Administration.
  79 p.
  Civil service -- Developing countries; Public administration -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
- A study of five strategies for soliciting contributions to stations WNET/KQED (Reports 003700), 1973 (Box 167)
  11 p. + appendices: tables, charts
  Public television -- New York (N.Y.); Public television -- United States; Public television -- New York (N.Y.); Public broadcasting -- New York (N.Y.); Public broadcasting -- United States; Eric Marder Associates, Inc.; Ford Foundation. Public Broadcasting
- Past and present Foundation funded research on race and ethnicity (Reports 003701), 1973 (Box 167)
  International Division;ER; National Affairs program
  PA73-182
  Ethnicity -- Research -- Developing countries; Ethnic conflict -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. International Division; Ford Foundation. Education and Research; Ford Foundation. National Affairs
- The effect of child mortality experience on subsequent fertility: an empirical analysis of Pakistan and Bangladesh data (Reports 003702), 1976 (Box 167)
  Report no. 29.
  26 p. + appendices: tables: 28 cm.
  Children -- Mortality -- Pakistan; Children -- Mortality -- Bangladesh; Infants -- Mortality -- Pakistan; Infants -- Mortality -- Bangladesh; Fertility, Human -- Research -- Pakistan; Fertility, Human -- Research -- Bangladesh; Population research -- Pakistan; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Demographic crisis: the impact of the Bangladesh Civil War (1971) on births and deaths in a rural area of Bangladesh (Reports 003703), 1975 (Box 167)
  [19] p.
  Population research -- Bangladesh
- Organization and management of the Division of Population Control and Family Planning Bangladesh (Reports 003704), 1975 (Box 167)
  07290171
  Support of program to provide improved management of family planning and population programs.
  119 p.: ill.
  Birth control -- Bangladesh; Bangladesh. Janasaṃkhyā Niẏantraṇa o Paribāra Parikalpanā Bibhāga
- Bangladesh: a new wheat country (Reports 003705), 1975 (Box 167)
  Report of a visit to Bangladesh from February 25-March 1, 1975 as part of an ongoing wheat development programme in Bangladesh.
  07500453
  Bangladesh Agricultural Research Council
  Support start-up activities of the appropriate agricultural technology cell.
  45 p.: 28 cm.
  Wheat production in Bangladesh, no. 3.
  Wheat -- Bangladesh; Agricultural development projects -- Bangladesh; Agriculture and state -- Bangladesh; Rural development -- Bangladesh; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; Bāṃlādeśa Kr̥shi Gabeshaṇā Kāunsila
- Appropriate agricultural technology in Bangladesh: Issues, needs, and suggestions (Reports 003706), 1975 (Box 167)
  Prepared for a Workshop on Appropriate Agricultural Technology held from February 6-8, 1975, under the sponsorship of the Bangladesh Agricultural Research Council (BARC), i.e., Bamladesa Krshi Gabeshana Kaunsila.
  International Division/Asia and the Pacific;Asia/Bangladesh
  iii, 31 p.: tables: 28 cm.
  Agriculture -- Technology transfer -- Bangladesh; Agricultural systems -- Bangladesh -- Finance; Agricultural development projects -- Bangladesh; Agriculture and state -- Bangladesh; Rural development -- Bangladesh; Bāṃlādeśa Kr̥shi Gabeshaṇā Kāunsila; Bāṃlādeśa Kr̥shi Gabeshaṇā Kāunsila
- Fertility control technology in Bangladesh (Reports 003707), 1976 (Box 167)
  Birth control -- Bangladesh; Fertility, Human -- Bangladesh; Population assistance -- Bangladesh; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Women's roles in Bangladesh development: a program assessment (Reports 003708), 1976 (Box 167)
  18 p. + appendices
  Women in development -- Bangladesh; Women in rural development -- Bangladesh; Women -- Employment -- Bangladesh; Women -- Bangladesh -- Economic conditions; Women -- Bangladesh -- Social conditionss; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- An assessment of Bangladesh's wheat production campaign 1975-76) (Reports 003709), 1976 (Box 167)
  Wheat research and production in Bangladesh, no. 4.
  Wheat -- Bangladesh; Agricultural productivity -- Bangladesh; Agriculture and state -- Bangladesh; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; Bāṃlādeśa Kr̥shi Gabeshaṇā Kāunsila
- Rural women in Bangladesh: Exploding some myths (Reports 003710), 1976 (Box 168)
  17 p. + appendices.
  Rural women -- Bangladesh; Women -- Bangladesh; Women in rural development -- Bangladesh; Women in development -- Bangladesh; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Science and agricultural technology for Bangladesh: A framework for policy analysis (Reports 003711), 1976 (Box 168)
  "The paper looks at the role of agricultural technology in a rural society and the need for explicit criteria to direct a strategy of technological development which is relevant to Bangladesh's resources, present situation and national objectives. The cri
  38 p.
  Agriculture -- Technology transfer -- Bangladesh; Rural development -- Bangladesh
- What's the use of a demonstration project (Reports 003712), 1976 (Box 168)
  "...the track record of rural health projects in developing countries is not good...The causes of this failure are complex, but certainly there have been enough demonstration projects so that no one could believe that a lack of pilot efforts for guides to
  28 p., 8 p. appendices.
  Rural health services -- Bangladesh; Rural health -- Bangladesh; Companiganj Project
- Recent fertility trends in Bangladesh: speculation on the role of biological factors and socioeconomic change (Reports 003713), 1976 (Box 168)
  This paper presents an analytic framework of human reproduction which facilitates an understanding of the possible roles of biologic and behavioral variables in affecting postulated trends in fertility in Bangladesh since 1960. The framework views fertil,NULL,NULL,NULL,NULL,UPRA,NULL,Report No. 46.
  17 p., 8 p. appendices.
  Reproductive health -- Bangladesh; Fertility, Human -- Bangladesh; Fertility, Human -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- The dynamics of contemporary famine (Reports 003714), 1977 (Box 168)
  "This paper presents data on the demographic impact of two contemporary Bangladesh famines, due to war (1971) and crop failure (1974). Fluctuations of births, deaths, and migrations are analyzed and disaggregated. From such empirical data, an analytical f
  26 p., 6 p. appendices, tables
  Famines -- Bangladesh; Malnutrition -- Bangladesh
- Bari-based Post Harvest Operations and Livestock Care: some observations and case studies (Reports 003715), 1977 (Box 168)
  Harvesting -- Bangladesh; Women in agriculture -- Research -- Bangladesh; Women farmers -- Bangladesh; Agriculture -- Bangladesh; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; Integrated Rural Development Programme (Bangladesh)
- The Ford Foundation's grant-making activities in Vietnam: A brief history and evaluation, 1973-1975 (Reports 003716) (Box 168)
  07590825
  Fellowship and research program for displaced Indochinese persons.
  Charity organization -- Vietnam; Vietnam War, 1961-1975; Philanthropy -- Vietnam; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Report of a study tour to Southeast Asia to learn about centralized population planning units: with recommendations for Bangladesh (Reports 003717), 1974 (Box 168)
  Population assistance -- Bangladesh; Population assistance -- Southeast Asia; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Educational television and educational media: A national service for education and training in Singapore (Reports 003718), 1968 (Box 168)
  PE;International Division/Asia and the Pacific
  L68-28
  Educational television programs -- Singapore; Television in education -- Singapore; Teaching -- Singapore -- Aids and devices; Teachers -- Training of -- Singapore; Education and state -- Singapore; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- The role of the Ford Foundation in the field of public employee labor relations, March 1968. (Reports 003719) (Box 168)
  L68-48.
  Civil service -- United States; Labor disputes -- United States; Industrial relations -- United States; Ford Foundation. National Affairs
- An approach to Foundation programming in the Middle East (Reports 003720), 1968 (Box 168)
  Charity organization -- Middle East; Philanthropy -- Middle East; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Report on the Seed Improvement Program to the Government of Saudi Arabia (Reports 003721), 1974 (Box 168)
  viii, 44 p.: 28 cm.
  Seed improvement program ...
  Seed projects -- Saudi Arabia; Seed industry and trade -- Saudi Arabia; Agricultural development projects -- Saudi Arabia; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa; Arid Lands Agricultural Development Program (Ford Foundation)
- Rural development at the grassroots: The catalyst role (Reports 003722), 1974 (Box 168)
  138 p.: ill., chart
  Rural development -- Developing countries; Technical assistance -- Developing countries; Charity organization -- Developing countries; Philanthropy -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Field trip report, Dominican Republic (Reports 003723), 1968 (Box 168)
  L68-105.
  41 p. + appendix
  Birth control -- Dominican Republic; Population assistance -- Dominican Republic; Public health -- Dominican Republic; Medical care -- Dominican Republic; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Field trip report, Jamaica, West Indies, October 5 to October 15 (Reports 003724), 1967 (Box 168)
  L68-103.
  Birth control -- Jamaica; Population research -- Jamaica; Population assistance -- Jamaica; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Instructional technology: Its status and potential in Pakistan (Reports 003725), 1969 (Box 168)
  A report to the Ford Foundation. --T.p.
  L68-189
  Educational technology -- Pakistan; Audio-visual education -- Pakistan; Mass media and education -- Pakistan; Education -- Pakistan; Education and state -- Pakistan; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- A plan to adapt television to the needs of education in Pakistan (Reports 003726), 1968 (Box 168)
  "Prepared for Mr. A.M.S. Ahmad ... Managing Director, Pakistan Television Corporation Limited." --T.p.
  124 p. + appendices: tables
  Television in education -- Pakistan; Educational television programs -- Pakistan; Instructional television programs -- Pakistan; Education and state -- Pakistan; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Major considerations in the application of satellite communications to India's Family Planning Programme (Reports 003727), 1968 (Box 168)
  " A discussion paper for the Joint Study Group for Satellite ETV, Ahmedabad, January 25, 1968." --T.p.
  L68-215.
  Communication in birth control -- India; Mass media in birth control -- India; Birth control -- India; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Some suggestions for moving forward with programming for satellite TV (Reports 003728), 1970 (Box 168)
  L68-215
  Direct broadcast satellite television -- India; Television -- Production and direction -- India; Television broadcasting -- India; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- The role of the humanities in desarrollo development: the Latin American case (Reports 003729), 1968 (Box 168)
  PA56-14;L58-265.
  82 p.: ill.: 28 cm.
  Humanities -- Latin America; Social sciences -- Latin America -- Philosophy; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Race and ethnicity: a research agenda (Reports 003730), 1974 (Box 169)
  "A Ford Foundation report prepared for the Task Force on Race and Ethnicity, January 1974." --T.p.
  103 p. + appendices: 28 cm.
  Ethnology -- Research -- United States; Ethnic groups -- Research -- United States; Race -- Social aspects -- United States; Minorities -- Research -- United States; Group identity -- United States; Social sciences -- Research -- United States
- Juvenile crime and ethnicity (Reports 003731), 1975 (Box 169)
  152 p. + appendices: 28 cm.
  Crime and race -- United States; Juvenile delinquency -- United States; Crime and race -- United States; Crime prevention -- United States -- Citizen participation; Ford Foundation. Social Development
- Ford Foundation Program in Argentina, 1960-1968, 1969. (Reports 003732) (Box 169)
  9, 14, 15 p.
  Philanthropy -- Argentina; Science and industry -- Argentina; Agricultural development projects -- Argentina; Industrialization -- Argentina; Education -- Argentina; Population control -- Argentina; Ford Foundation Program Development -- Argentina
- The current state of agricultural economics research in Pakistan (Reports 003733), 1970 (Box 169)
  L68-445;L69-461.
  Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Research -- Pakistan; Agriculture and state -- Pakistan; Agricultural economists -- Pakistan -- Supply and demand; Ford Foundation. Field Office Islamabad; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Economic situation in Southeast Asia (Reports 003734), 1969 (Box 169)
  L68-460
  26 p.: table
  Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Southeast Asia; Agriculture and state -- Southeast Asia; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Electronic communications: public policy issues and research activities (Reports 003735), 1967 (Box 169)
  xi, 214 p.
  Communication policy -- United States; Mass media policy -- United States; Mass media -- Law and legislation -- United States; Ford Foundation. Office of the Secretary
- The Ford Foundation in Greece (Reports 003736), 1968 (Box 169)
  Charity organization -- Greece; Economic assistance -- Greece; Endowments -- Greece -- Evaluation; Philanthropy -- Greece; Ford Foundation. International Division
- Report to the Ford Foundation representative in India: International Legal Center (Reports 003737), 1968 (Box 169)
  Review of law-related projects supported by the Foundation.
  ii, 28 p.
  Law -- Study and teaching -- India; Law teachers -- India; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- The impact of U.S. military expenditures on the Thai economy (Reports 003738), 1968 (Box 169)
  13 p.: ill., tables, charts
  Military administration -- Thailand; Ford Foundation. Field Office Bangkok; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- A suggested multiple cropping, soil and water management project in the Chiengmai Area (Reports 003739), 1968 (Box 169)
  A discussion paper prepared for the Bangkok Regional Office of the Ford Foundation. --T.p.
  Multiple cropping -- Thailand; Soil management -- Thailand; Irrigation projects -- Thailand; Agricultural development projects -- Thailand; Agricultural extension work -- Thailand; Ford Foundation. Field Office Bangkok; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Development of local competence, Kenya meeting of representatives (Reports 003740), 1968 (Box 169)
  "Agenda paper, session VII, emerging issues June 8, 1968." --p.1.
  PAPER Conference (1968 June 6-8: Nairobi, Kenya)
  Technical assistance -- Developing countries -- Evaluation; Charity organization -- Developing countries -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. International Division
- Report of a consulting survey in Pakistan (Reports 003741), 1968 (Box 169)
  Public administration -- Pakistan; Education -- Research -- Pakistan; Universities and colleges -- Pakistan -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Development and the Ford Foundation in Mexico and Central America (Reports 003742), 1968 (Box 169)
  "Presentation to the Casa Jones Meeting, October 6, 1968." --p.1.
  Charity organization -- Mexico; Charity organization -- Central America; Philanthropy -- Mexico; Philanthropy -- Central America; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- The Urban Institute, 1968-1978: an evaluation of its performance, prospects and financial problems (Reports 003743) (Box 169)
  Policy sciences -- Research -- United States; Research institutes -- United States; Urban Institute Evaluation
- The Intensive Agricultural District Program in India's Agricultural Development (Reports 003744), 1960 (Box 169)
  Address given at Orientation and Training Program for Package Program.
  Asia/India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
  06000333
  Intensive Agricultural Districts Programme; Agriculture -- India; Agricultural development projects -- India; India
- Manual of procedures import of scientific equipment for University of Delhi, Delhi (Reports 003745), 1970 (Box 169)
  06700444
  The University of Delhi
  Strengthening teaching and research at the University.
  14 p. + attachments: forms: 28 cm.
  Science -- India -- Equipment and supplies; Science -- Study and teaching -- India; Science -- Research -- India; Education, Higher -- India; Endowments -- India -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Field Office New Delhi; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; University of Delhi
- Report on consultancy, IEM Division, population control and family planning directorate (Reports 003746), 1978 (Box 170)
  Birth control -- Bangladesh; Population assistance -- Bangladesh; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Attitudes toward instructional television (Reports 003747), 1965 (Box 170)
  A report prepared for The Ford Foundation. --T.p.
  06290387
  Preparation and publication of reports on instructional television.
  vi, 67 p. + appendices: tables, forms: 28 cm.